I think that we we learn this too much thing also because we live in a society, particularly in a Western society of America, that has been created by white male colonizers who have not by any means given a damn about emotions.
They are driven by greed and they are driven by power and that greed and power are not about emotional.
The only emotional intelligence that they have is how to manipulate others.
The people who are seeking greed and power are only emotionally intelligent for the sake of harming others.
So we don't live in a setup that honors emotional intelligence as a community building tactic.
We honor emotional intelligence as a community breaking tactic.
That is the Willie Lynch syndrome.
So it is no wonder that we have such a hard goddamn time breaking through to the other side and being able to consider these things as valuable.
But they are.
You're being told you're too much because we are raised in a situation of deficit.